Hello!
Welcome to this video in which we'll
look at the different types of waste
associated with lean management.
You will often hear about the seven wastes of
lean, which are common amongst practitioners.
These are 1.
Transport, 2.
Inventory, 3.
Motion, 4.
Weighting, 5.
Overproduction, 6.
Overprocessing.
7.
Defects.
In this video, we are also going
to look at the eighth waste.
Unutilised talent is specifically related to
manufacturing management, whereas the first
seven are related to manufacturing processes.
Let's look at each of these wastes in more detail.
Transport waste occurs when movement of any
material isn't part of the immediate production.
Unnecessary movement of materials,
products or people which can lead to
increased costs and risk of damage or loss.
For example, transporting raw
materials or finished products between
sites over long distances or having
multiple handoffs between departments.
Inventory.
Too much stock leads to more
than just transport waste.
Lean processing is all about
just in time manufacturing.
If production isn't lean, raw materials may be
over ordered, meaning they need to be stored.
Cash flow is affected as money is being spent on
stock that might not be needed for months to come.
We can see here that inventory waste
can be a result of inefficient processes
and unbalanced production processes.
Motion.
Any job that requires excess movement,
such as reaching, bending, gathering
tools or moving equipment is a waste.
Motion waste is usually caused by ineffective
layout and poor workplace organisation.
We've seen in Unit 2 that there are many
factors to consider when setting up an
activity workplace and motion is another.
Lack of visual controls, poor processes, and
documentation will also lead to motion waste.
Waiting.
Any waiting time in the
production process is waste.
For example, waiting for approval,
waiting for equipment to be repaired,
or waiting for materials to arrive.
Whilst these might not always be unavoidable,
they can be greatly reduced through strong
processes, maintenance of equipment, and
consistent working methods over production.
As with inventory waste, overproduction
procedures have similar waste, although
this happens for different reasons.
When items are produced faster than needed,
it's commonly known as a push system.
It can be caused by poor planning or
teams working at different speeds.
Maybe there's new workers in one team, which
has slowed them down and lack of communication.
Alternatively, the overproduction may be
down to incorrectly placed automation.
Overprocessing.
It's important to ensure that processing is
right for the job in hand, and that nothing
additional to what's needed is being done.
This could include producing items
that are above the quality needed,
writing too many or too complicated
processes, and over refining processes.
In summary, any unnecessary work that
results in more time and effort than is
needed is considered over processing.
Defects.
A good quality control process should minimise
defects, and it's therefore important to have
checks in place throughout the production.
Defects detected early in the production
can stop difficulties occurring for
teams further along, which can impact on
overproduction, waiting, and inventory.
Where products are sent out with defects,
customers will return them, which leads to further
storage and time spent on customer complaints.
Unutilised talent.
All of the wastes we've looked at so
far relate to manufacturing processes.
As mentioned at the beginning of
this video, unutilised talent is the
only waste relating to management.
It's a result of employees not being
engaged in processes, talent being wasted,
or work being performed unnecessarily.
Knowing and utilising employees
strengths results in better productivity.
It's also important that employees are
encouraged to share knowledge, and we
considered the benefits of this in Unit 1.